<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Migrating Enterprise Scale Cloud Foundry Apps to Kubernetes on Documentation for Konveyor projects</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/</link><description>Recent content in Migrating Enterprise Scale Cloud Foundry Apps to Kubernetes on Documentation for Konveyor projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 12:06:32 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>1. Collect</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/1collect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/1collect/</guid><description>Note: This is an optional step. If you are not familiar with Cloud Foundry or you do not want to collect information from your running app, skip to Customizing the output.
To analyze the running application in Cloud Foundry (CF), the Move2Kube CLI tool provides a command called collect. As the name suggests, the collect command collects information about applications running in the cloud.
For collecting information from a CF running instance, you might require cf CLI for logging into Cloud Foundry.</description></item><item><title>2. Plan</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/2plan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 12:08:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/2plan/</guid><description>We start by planning the migration. During the plan phase, Move2Kube will analyze the files in the source directory, detect what services exist, create a plan on how to containerize them using Dockerfiles, and transform them into Kubernetes deployments, services, ingress, etc.
In order to do the planning, Move2Kube has a large number of built-in transformers for different languages and platforms. Each transformer walks through the source directory from top to bottom and tries to find files that it recognizes.</description></item><item><title>3. Transform</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/3transform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 12:08:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/move2kube/tutorials/cfappstok8/3transform/</guid><description>Now we can run the transformation according to the plan file generated in the previous step. The transformation phase runs all of the transformers again, but this time the transformers will use the plan to generate the output files.
During this process, the transformers might run into situations where it requires some more information to generate the output. In order to get this information, it will ask the user some questions.</description></item></channel></rss>