<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubernetes on Konveyor</title><link>http://konveyor.io/tags/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Konveyor</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.io/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Year in the CNCF Sandbox- Konveyor's Reflective Journey</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/one-year-cncf-sandbox-konveyor-reflective-journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/one-year-cncf-sandbox-konveyor-reflective-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/savitharaghunathan">Savitha Raghunathan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been an exceptional year for Konveyor since its admission into the CNCF in July 2022. Since then, the project has undergone a series of transformative changes and remarkable achievements, guided by a newly &lt;a href="https://github.com/konveyor/community/blob/main/Charter.md">updated charter&lt;/a> that has refocused Konveyor&amp;rsquo;s mission towards refactoring and replatforming legacy applications. In this post, we invite you to join us on a journey down memory lane as we celebrate the numerous milestones, both big and small, that our dedicated contributors have accomplished over the past year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modernize Petclinic App to Kubernetes Using Konveyor</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/modernize-petclinic-to-k8s-using-konveyor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/modernize-petclinic-to-k8s-using-konveyor/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/savitharaghunathan">Savitha Raghunathan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Konveyor aims to surface insights on applications at scale to empower enterprise users to make better-informed decisions related to modernization activities. When it comes to migrating applications to Kubernetes (K8s), it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that some applications can be ported without any major issues. However, there are certain edge cases where applications may encounter difficulties during the migration process. One such edge case we will focus on in this tutorial involves Hazelcast. Hazelcast is an open-source in-memory data grid that provides distributed caching and data synchronization capabilities. In this tutorial, we will use Hazelcast as the session backing store. During the migration of an application utilizing Hazelcast, some issues arise due to the distributed nature of Hazelcast and the dynamic nature of a Kubernetes environment. In this specific case, network connectivity and discovery issues impact the functionality of the petclinic application.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Konveyor v0.2.1 Release Announcement</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/release-announcement-0-2-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/release-announcement-0-2-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce the release of Konveyor 0.2.1! This release supports various features, like migration waves, integration with Jira, and other valuable minor updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key Highlights of Konveyor 0.2.1:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Migration waves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jira Integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minor improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="migration-waves">Migration Waves:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We are excited to introduce a significant addition to the Konveyor project, aimed at providing enhanced value throughout the migration process. We recognized the need to address the planning aspect required to scale the migration process across entire application portfolio. When dealing with a large-scale portfolio containing hundreds or even thousands of applications, it becomes impractical to execute the migration process in one go. To tackle this challenge, we have introduced the ability for Konveyor to define migration waves, allowing for an iterative and manageable approach. By breaking down the portfolio into waves, we enable a more sophisticated process that in the future we expect will automate the calculation of these waves based on various criteria. This feature empowers users to scale adoption efforts effectively, ensuring a seamless and efficient migration experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflecting on Large-Scale Cloud-Native Modernizations at KubeCon 23</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/reflecting-on-large-scale-cloud-native-modernizations-at-kubecon-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/reflecting-on-large-scale-cloud-native-modernizations-at-kubecon-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Migrating large infrastructures from an on-premise, monolithic, traditional IT management approach
to a modern cloud-native Kubernetes-based ecosystem is a daunting task.
Christopher Nuland (Konveyor Ambassador) led a conversation with Jared Burk and Valentina Rodriguez Sosa, Red Hat; James Bench, Maximus
about the different migrations they have completed and the challenges they experienced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chris and Valentina summarized the key 6 takeaways that combined questions from the audience
and a summary of the panel discussion held at the KubeCon 23 in AMSTERDAM.
&lt;img src="panel_blog.png" alt="Konveyor">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application Modernization Report Shows Need For Kubernetes-specific Migration Tooling</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/application-modernization-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/application-modernization-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>Konveyor is a community of people passionate about helping others modernize and migrate their applications to the hybrid cloud by building tools, identifying patterns, and providing advice on how to break down monoliths, adopt containers, and embrace Kubernetes. To do so the Konveyor community is currently working on five projects to help users rehost, replatform, and refactor their applications to Kubernetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While conversations with users and data from various sources gave us some visibility into how migrations were taking place, we wanted to inform our priorities with recent detailed data. To do so, Red Hat, a Konveyor community contributor, sponsored a survey of 600 IT decision makers, backend developers, and software architects in the US, UK, and English-speaking Asia-Pacific (APAC) to better understand the application modernization landscape.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>