<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Konveyor on Documentation for Konveyor projects</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/</link><description>Recent content in Konveyor on Documentation for Konveyor projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Administrator view tasks</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/admintasks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 15:16:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/admintasks/</guid><description>The administrator view is intended to be used by administrators to set up the Tackle instance environment. Credentials This management module enables administrators to create and manage credentials for access to private repositories. It also allows for the architects to assign the credentials to applications without knowing their contents. Key credential attributes to have before starting the procedure include:
Name Description (optional) Type (Souce control, Maven settings file, Proxy) Created by Important There are three types of credentials.</description></item><item><title>Views</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/views/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 14:59:53 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/views/</guid><description>The latest version of Tackle has the Developers view and the new Architects view to support the three main roles of users:
Administrators: Has access to some application-wide configuration parameters that other users can consume but not change or browse.
Example actions: Define Git credentials, Maven settings, .xml files.
Architects: Often the technical leads for the migration project that can create and modify applications and information related to it. The Architects do not need to have access to sensitive information, but can consume it.</description></item><item><title>Seeding Instances</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/instances/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 14:59:46 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/instances/</guid><description>Tackle instances have key parameters that are configured in the Controls window prior to migration by the project architect and can be added and edited as needed.
These parameters define applications and individuals, teams, verticals or areas within an organization affected or participating in the migration.
Stakeholders Stakeholder groups Job functions Business services Tag types Tags Seeding Tackle instance The steps to creating and configuring a Tackle instance can be performed in any order, but the suggested order below is the most efficient for creating stakeholders and tags.</description></item><item><title>Installing Konveyor</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/installation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 14:59:30 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/installation/</guid><description>Follow the steps below to provision the minikube cluster and install Tackle 2.0.
Provisioning Minikube Follow the steps below to provision minikube for single users deploying Tackle on a workstation. These steps will configure minikube and enable:
Ingress so the Tackle tool can publish outside of the Kubernetes cluster. Operator lifecycle manager (OLM) addon. (OpenShift has OLM installed out of the box but Kubernetes does not.) Procedure
Provision the minikube cluster with these recommended parameters.</description></item><item><title>Assessing and analyzing applications</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/assessanalyze/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 14:59:11 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/assessanalyze/</guid><description>Tackle core functions are assessing and analyzing the applications for migration and are performed on the Application inventory page. Assessing applications Follow the steps below to facilitate discussion of application migration.
Procedure
Click Application inventory in the left menu in the Development view. Click the checkbox to the left of the application being assessed. Note: Only one application can be assessed at a time.
Click the Assess button. Select the Stakeholders and Stakeholder groups from the drop-down lists to track who contributed to the assessment for future reference.</description></item><item><title>Adding applications</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/addapps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 14:58:52 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/konveyor/addapps/</guid><description>Applications can be added to Tackle by creating new applications from scratch manually or by importing them. Tackle applications are defined by manually entered and pre-defined attributes:
Name (manual) Description (manual) Business service (pre-defined) Tags (pre-defined) Source code Binary Creating a new application Follow the steps below to add a new application to the inventory for assessment and analysis.
Note: Before starting this procedure, it is helpful to set up business services, check tags and tag types, and create additions as needed.</description></item></channel></rss>