<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Migrating virtual machines on Documentation for Konveyor projects</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/</link><description>Recent content in Migrating virtual machines on Documentation for Konveyor projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:03:39 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migration plan options</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/migrateoptions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:04:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/migrateoptions/</guid><description>On the Migration plans page of the Forklift web console, click the Options menu kebab beside a migration plan to access the following options:
Edit: Edit the details of a migration plan. A migration plan cannot be edited while it is running or after it has completed successfully. Duplicate: Create a new migration plan with the same virtual machines (VMs), parameters, mappings, and hooks as an existing plan. Use this feature for the following tasks: Migrating VMs to a different namespace.</description></item><item><title>Migrating virtual machines using the command line</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/migratecli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:04:06 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/migratecli/</guid><description>Follow the steps below to migrate virtual machines (VMs) to KubeVirt using the command line (CLI) by creating Forklift custom resources (CRs) and specifying:
A name for cluster-scoped CRs. A name and a namespace for namespace-scoped CRs. Prerequisites
Must be logged in as a user with cluster-admin privileges.
VMware only:
Must have the vCenter SHA-1 fingerprint. Must create a VMware Virtual Disk Development Kit (VDDK) image in a secure registry that is accessible to all clusters.</description></item><item><title>Migrating virtual machines using the web console</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/migrateweb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 10:03:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/migrateweb/</guid><description>Migrate virtual machines (VMs) to KubeVirt using the Forklift web console by performing the folloing tasks:
Adding source and destination providers Creating network and storage mapping Creating and running a migration plan Prerequisites
Ensure that all Prerequisites are set. VMware only: Create a VMware Virtual Disk Development Kit (VDDK) image. Adding source providers Follow the procedures below to add VMware or oVirt source providers using the Forklift web console.
Adding a VMware source provider Add a VMware source provider by using the Forklift web console.</description></item><item><title>Canceling a migration</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/cancelmigrate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:30:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/cancelmigrate/</guid><description>Follow the steps below to cancel the migration of some or all virtual machines (VMs) while a migration plan is in progress by using the Forklift web console.
Procedure
Click Migration Plans. Click the name of a running migration plan to view the migration details. Select one or more VMs and click Cancel. Click Yes, cancel to confirm the cancellation. The status of the VM shows canceled in the Migration details by VM list.</description></item><item><title>Advanced migration options</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/advancedmigrate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:04:36 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/migratingvms/advancedmigrate/</guid><description>Changing precopy intervals for warm migration Follow the steps below to change the snapshot interval by patching the ForkliftController custom resource (CR).
Procedure
Patch the ForkliftController CR: $ kubectl patch forkliftcontroller/&amp;lt;forklift-controller&amp;gt; -n konveyor-forklift -p &amp;#39;{&amp;#34;spec&amp;#34;: {&amp;#34;controller_precopy_interval&amp;#34;: &amp;lt;60&amp;gt;}}&amp;#39; --type=merge (1) Note: The Creating custom rules for the Validation service section below refers to the callout in the sample code above.
Specify the precopy interval in minutes. The default value is 60. Note: The forklift-controller pod does not need to be restarted.</description></item></channel></rss>