<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Konveyor</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Konveyor</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Konveyor AI 0.1.0 is here!</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2025/kai-release-announcement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2025/kai-release-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/savitharaghunathan">Savitha Raghunathan&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://github.com/JonathanR19">Jonathan Recinos&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After months of ideas, development, and feedback from early users and contributors, we&amp;rsquo;re excited to share the first official release of &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://github.com/konveyor/editor-extensions/releases/tag/v0.1.0">Konveyor AI 0.1.0&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release is a significant step forward for the Konveyor project, and for anyone working through the complex journey of application modernization. It marks the beginning of &lt;strong>developer-focused, AI-assisted modernization&lt;/strong> built with community input and open collaboration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-konveyor-ai">What is Konveyor AI?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Konveyor AI (Kai)&lt;/strong> provides real-time insights to help developers and migrators identify and refactor deprecated or outdated code. As a developer modernizes an application with Kai, they&amp;rsquo;ll see detailed issues and their location, solutions with the reasoning for it, and code suggestions that can be automatically implemented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Incident Storage in Kai - A Deep Dive</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/kai-incident-storage-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/kai-incident-storage-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: Jonah Sussman (&lt;a href="https://www.GitHub.com/jonahsussman/">GitHub&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonahsussman/">LinkedIn&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="mailto:jsussman@redhat.com">E-mail&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The process of modernizing an application is complex and time-consuming. Despite
our best efforts as software engineers with things like &lt;a href="https://semver.org/">semantic
versioning&lt;/a>, detailed release notes, and thorough testing,
modernizing a single application is an intimidating task.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This kind of work is often one of the most unglamorous, and error-prone tasks
that developers have to do. It involves rewriting large portions of the
codebase, which can be daunting for even the most battle-hardened of developers.
There&amp;rsquo;s an interconnected web of functions, classes, and modules that all depend
on each other. One wrong move and the whole thing can come crashing down.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Konveyor AI (Kai) Roadmap 2024</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/kai-roadmap-2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/kai-roadmap-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/jwmatthews">John Matthews&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post shares the roadmap for &lt;a href="https://github.com/konveyor/kai">Konveyor AI (Kai)&lt;/a> as of summer 2024.
&lt;em>For a recap of what is Konveyor AI (Kai) please see our prior post: &lt;a href="http://konveyor.io/blog/kai-deep-dive-2024/">Kai - Generative AI Applied to Application Modernization&lt;/a>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The roadmap is organized by themes of functionality, each focusing on a specific aspect of the project&amp;rsquo;s development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roadmap Outline:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#purpose">Purpose&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#maturity">Maturity&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#guiding-principles">Guiding Principles&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#themes">Themes&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#milestones">Milestones&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#future-areas-to-consider">Future Areas to Consider&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#access-to-early-builds">Access to Early Builds&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="purpose">Purpose&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What is the purpose of Konveyor AI?&lt;/strong>
Kai intends to improve the economics of re-platforming and refactoring applications to Kubernetes and cloud-native technologies via use of Generative AI leveraging data in Konveyor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kai - Generative AI Applied to Application Modernization</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/kai-deep-dive-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/kai-deep-dive-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/jwmatthews">John Matthews&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Konveyor AI or &amp;ldquo;Kai&amp;rdquo;, is an early effort of Generative AI applied to Application Modernization being explored under the Konveyor Ecosystem at &lt;a href="https://github.com/konveyor-ecosystem/kai">konveyor-ecosystem/kai&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kai implements a &lt;a href="https://www.promptingguide.ai/techniques/rag">Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG)&lt;/a> approach that leverages data from Konveyor to help generate code suggestions to aid migrating legacy code bases to a different technology. The intent of this RAG approach is to shape the code suggestions to be similar to how an organization has solved problems in the past, without additional fine-tuning of the model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Konveyor at KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2024 EU Paris</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/konveyor-kiosk-at-kubecon-europe-2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2024/konveyor-kiosk-at-kubecon-europe-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/savitharaghunathan">Savitha Raghunathan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attend KubeCon + CloudNativeCon Europe we are eager to meet you!!
You&amp;rsquo;ll have multiple chances to engage with the Konveyor project and connect with other members of the Konveyor community.
This event provides an excellent opportunity to ask questions, interact with the Konveyor team in person, provide feedback, and build connections within the Konveyor community.
We are looking forward to meeting you there!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kubecon--cloudnativecon-project-pavilion">KubeCon + CloudNativeCon Project Pavilion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Be sure to visit our kiosk at PP3-A in the &lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/program/project-engagement/#project-pavilion">project pavilion&lt;/a>
to learn more about Konveyor and pick up some cool swag and stickers!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>State of Application Modernization Report 2024</title><link>http://konveyor.io/modernization-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/modernization-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>Organizations take a variety of different approaches to modernizing their applications as they target improving security, reliability, and scalability. Relative to our last survey, two years ago, we’re seeing a greater emphasis on updating legacy applications and infrastructure over building new cloud applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-survey">About the survey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Konveyor community member Red Hat partnered with research firm Illuminas to better understand how organizations plan to approach application modernization and migration—and what they consider success to look like. In all, 1,000 responses were gathered with half coming from the US and the balance split evenly between the United Kingdom (UK) and English-speaking Asia-Pacific (APAC). Half of the respondents were IT decision makers, a quarter were back-end developers, and a quarter software architects. Most respondents were large enterprises with more than 5,000 employees with the rest working for medium enterprises. A variety of industries including retail, software development, finance, and telecoms were represented.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Konveyor Kiosk at KubeCon + CloudNativeCon 2023 NA Chicago</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/konveyor-kiosk-at-kubecon-north-america-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/konveyor-kiosk-at-kubecon-north-america-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/savitharaghunathan">Savitha Raghunathan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to attend KubeCon + CloudNativeCon North America, we are eager to meet you!! You&amp;rsquo;ll have multiple chances to engage with the Konveyor project and connect with other members of the Konveyor community. This event provides an excellent opportunity to ask questions, interact with the Konveyor team in person, provide feedback, and build connections within the Konveyor community. We are looking forward to meeting you there!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One Year in the CNCF Sandbox- Konveyor's Reflective Journey</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/one-year-cncf-sandbox-konveyor-reflective-journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/one-year-cncf-sandbox-konveyor-reflective-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/savitharaghunathan">Savitha Raghunathan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been an exceptional year for Konveyor since its admission into the CNCF in July 2022. Since then, the project has undergone a series of transformative changes and remarkable achievements, guided by a newly &lt;a href="https://github.com/konveyor/community/blob/main/Charter.md">updated charter&lt;/a> that has refocused Konveyor&amp;rsquo;s mission towards refactoring and replatforming legacy applications. In this post, we invite you to join us on a journey down memory lane as we celebrate the numerous milestones, both big and small, that our dedicated contributors have accomplished over the past year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modernize Petclinic App to Kubernetes Using Konveyor</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/modernize-petclinic-to-k8s-using-konveyor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/modernize-petclinic-to-k8s-using-konveyor/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Author&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://github.com/savitharaghunathan">Savitha Raghunathan&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Konveyor aims to surface insights on applications at scale to empower enterprise users to make better-informed decisions related to modernization activities. When it comes to migrating applications to Kubernetes (K8s), it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that some applications can be ported without any major issues. However, there are certain edge cases where applications may encounter difficulties during the migration process. One such edge case we will focus on in this tutorial involves Hazelcast. Hazelcast is an open-source in-memory data grid that provides distributed caching and data synchronization capabilities. In this tutorial, we will use Hazelcast as the session backing store. During the migration of an application utilizing Hazelcast, some issues arise due to the distributed nature of Hazelcast and the dynamic nature of a Kubernetes environment. In this specific case, network connectivity and discovery issues impact the functionality of the petclinic application.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Konveyor v0.2.1 Release Announcement</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/release-announcement-0-2-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/release-announcement-0-2-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are thrilled to announce the release of Konveyor 0.2.1! This release supports various features, like migration waves, integration with Jira, and other valuable minor updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key Highlights of Konveyor 0.2.1:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Migration waves&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jira Integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minor improvements&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="migration-waves">Migration Waves:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We are excited to introduce a significant addition to the Konveyor project, aimed at providing enhanced value throughout the migration process. We recognized the need to address the planning aspect required to scale the migration process across entire application portfolio. When dealing with a large-scale portfolio containing hundreds or even thousands of applications, it becomes impractical to execute the migration process in one go. To tackle this challenge, we have introduced the ability for Konveyor to define migration waves, allowing for an iterative and manageable approach. By breaking down the portfolio into waves, we enable a more sophisticated process that in the future we expect will automate the calculation of these waves based on various criteria. This feature empowers users to scale adoption efforts effectively, ensuring a seamless and efficient migration experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflecting on Large-Scale Cloud-Native Modernizations at KubeCon 23</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/reflecting-on-large-scale-cloud-native-modernizations-at-kubecon-23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2023/reflecting-on-large-scale-cloud-native-modernizations-at-kubecon-23/</guid><description>&lt;p>Migrating large infrastructures from an on-premise, monolithic, traditional IT management approach
to a modern cloud-native Kubernetes-based ecosystem is a daunting task.
Christopher Nuland (Konveyor Ambassador) led a conversation with Jared Burk and Valentina Rodriguez Sosa, Red Hat; James Bench, Maximus
about the different migrations they have completed and the challenges they experienced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Chris and Valentina summarized the key 6 takeaways that combined questions from the audience
and a summary of the panel discussion held at the KubeCon 23 in AMSTERDAM.
&lt;img src="panel_blog.png" alt="Konveyor">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Community Update: Konveyor Refocuses Efforts on Replatforming and Refactoring Use Cases</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/community-update-konveyor-refocuses-efforts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/community-update-konveyor-refocuses-efforts/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the latest &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jyd3mpvVCC4">community update&lt;/a>, we revealed upcoming changes to the Konveyor Project. These adjustments are designed to solve the most important application modernizations problem better and to encourage participation with our community. Here’s what we announced:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We will solely focus on solving for the replatforming and refactoring use cases.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It’s easier to contribute and collaborate with Konveyor thanks to our new special interest group (SIG) model.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can learn the Konveyor project, see upcoming features, and give us feedback at our workshop — part of the OpenShift Commons Gathering at KubeCon NA 2022. &lt;a href="https://hopin.com/events/openshift-commons-gathering-2022-at-kubecon-na-detroit">Register for the Gathering&lt;/a> to secure your spot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tackle 2.1 is available, future Tackle releases will be branded Konveyor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Konveyor roadmap includes migration wave management, multi language support, and integrations with modernization tools.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can get the details of each announcement below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tackle 2.1 release</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-1-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-1-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the major milestone that &lt;a href="http://konveyor.io/blog/tackle-2-new-capabilities/">Tackle 2.0&lt;/a> represented, the community has continued gathering feedback from the field to further polish the feature set and provide value in the context of modernization, migration and adoption projects. This has led to Tackle 2.1, available now in &lt;a href="https://operatorhub.io/">operatorhub.io&lt;/a>, a minor release that has been focused on stabilizing the project and providing a more streamlined user experience, while still delivering some new tooling. The new features include the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Konveyor is now a Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) Sandbox project</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/konveyor-is-a-cncf-sandbox-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/konveyor-is-a-cncf-sandbox-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Big news! Konveyor was recently accepted as a Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) Sandbox project 🎉&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-are-we-so-excited-about-this">Why are we so excited about this?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is a huge milestone in our mission to accelerate the movement of applications to run on Kubernetes with an open-source approach. With the added credibility of our sandbox status, we can more easily attract and convince others to adopt and contribute to Konveyor. The result will be more effective open source tools that everyone can use to adopt Kubernetes and cloud-native technology faster!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Method to Measure and Manage Technical Debt</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/measure-manage-technical-debt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/measure-manage-technical-debt/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a software developer, technical debt is all those little things that you feel are hampering the efficiency of your coding. These are the issues that you (or your manager) choose to handle next time, because of the urgency of the current release. But sometimes, by the time you get to them, they have become so big you do not know where to start solving them. The difficult part is that decisions we make regarding technical debt have to balance between short term and long term implications of accumulating such debt, emphasizing the need to properly assess and address it when planning development cycles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tackle 2: New capabilities for modernizing applications to leverage Kubernetes</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-new-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-new-capabilities/</guid><description>&lt;p>By Ramón Román Nissen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re thrilled to announce that Tackle 2.0 is now available in &lt;a href="https://operatorhub.io/">operatorhub.io&lt;/a>. This new release marks a major milestone for the Tackle project, with a new architecture focused on enhancing performance, scalability and more importantly, extensibility of the tooling available in the Tackle toolkit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This version includes the seamless integration with the analysis capabilities of the Windup project, enabling Tackle to effectively manage, assess and now also analyze applications to have a holistic view at your portfolio when dealing with large scale modernization and Kubernetes adoption initiatives. This is essential to provide key insights that allow Architects leading these massive projects to make informed decisions, thus reducing risks and making the required effort measurable and predictable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application Modernization Report Shows Need For Kubernetes-specific Migration Tooling</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/application-modernization-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/application-modernization-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>Konveyor is a community of people passionate about helping others modernize and migrate their applications to the hybrid cloud by building tools, identifying patterns, and providing advice on how to break down monoliths, adopt containers, and embrace Kubernetes. To do so the Konveyor community is currently working on five projects to help users rehost, replatform, and refactor their applications to Kubernetes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While conversations with users and data from various sources gave us some visibility into how migrations were taking place, we wanted to inform our priorities with recent detailed data. To do so, Red Hat, a Konveyor community contributor, sponsored a survey of 600 IT decision makers, backend developers, and software architects in the US, UK, and English-speaking Asia-Pacific (APAC) to better understand the application modernization landscape.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Konveyor Community HackFest</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2021/konveyor-community-hackfest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2021/konveyor-community-hackfest/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>January 31–February 4, 2022. 9 a.m.–5 p.m. EST each day&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get free hands-on experience migrating different workload types to Kubernetes with open source tools and community engineer support. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1DGM5x8x4UyFAUQPkrJoVicnVWmovPbRqumLeotHtugI/edit?ts=61a8ce49">Register to get the calendar invite&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Konveyor community has developed multiple use cases for you to learn time- and cost-efficient ways to migrate to Kubernetes. During this HackFest, if something is missing, not working as expected, or you simply get stuck — you can open a GitHub issue or get support from the community engineers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploring a Metrics-Driven Approach to Transformation</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2021/metrics-driven-approach-to-transformation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2021/metrics-driven-approach-to-transformation/</guid><description>&lt;p>My team has been working with organizations adopting containers, Kubernetes, and Red Hat OpenShift for more than three years now. When we started providing professional services around enterprise Kubernetes, it became clear we needed a program-level framework for adopting containers that spelled out the activities of multiple project teams. Some participants would be focused on container platform management and operations, some on continuous delivery, some on the application lifecycle, and others on cross-cutting process transformation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating Faster with Direct Migration</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2021/direct-migration/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2021/direct-migration/</guid><description>&lt;p>In MTC 1.4.0, a new feature called Direct Migration is available that will yield significant time savings for most customers migrating persistent volumes and/or internal images. Direct Migration enables the migration of persistent volumes and internal images directly from the source cluster to the destination cluster without an intermediary replication repository. This introduces a significant performance enhancement while also providing better error and progress reporting information back to the end-user.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>