<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installing Forklift on Documentation for Konveyor projects</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/</link><description>Recent content in Installing Forklift on Documentation for Konveyor projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 09:57:41 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrading Forklift</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/upgrade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 14:36:19 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/upgrade/</guid><description>Follow the steps below to upgrade the Forklift Operator using the OKD web console.
Important: Do not skip a release when upgrading. For example, upgrade 2.0 to 2.1 and then 2.1 to 2.2.
If upgrading from 2.2 to 2.3, see the ### Forklift 2.2 to 2.3 Upgrade Notes section after the procedure.
Procedure
Open the OKD web console. Click Operators, Installed Operators, Migration Tookit for Virtualization Operator, then Subscription. Change the update channel to the correct release.</description></item><item><title>Uninstalling Forklift</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/uninstall/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 14:16:26 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/uninstall/</guid><description>Forklift can be uninstalled using the OKD web console or the command line interface (CLI).
Uninstalling Forklift with the OKD web console Follow the steps below to uninstall Forklift using the OKD web console to delete the konveyor-forklift project and custom resource definitions (CRDs).
Prerequisites
Logged in as a user with cluster-admin privileges. Procedure
Click Home and then Projects. Locate the konveyor-forklift project. Select Delete Project from the Options menu kebab on the right side of the project.</description></item><item><title>Installing the Forklift Operator</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/installation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:57:06 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/installation/</guid><description>The Forklift Operator can be installed using the OKD web console or the command line interface (CLI).
Installing the Forklift Operator using the OKD web console Follow the steps below to install the Forklift Operator using the OKD web console.
Prerequisites
OKD 4.10 installed. KubeVirt Operator installed. Procedure
Log in with cluster-admin permissions. Open the OKD web console, click Operators, then OperatorHub. Use the Filter by keyword field to search for forklift-operator.</description></item><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/prereqs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 15:56:20 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/forklift/installingforklift/prereqs/</guid><description>The following prerequisites ensure the environment is prepared for migration.
Software compatibility guidelines Install compatible software versions with Forklift using the table below.
Forklift OKD KubeVirt VMware vSphere oVirt 2.3 4.10 4.10 6.5 or later 4.4.9 or later Storage support and default modes Forklift uses the following default volume and access modes for supported storage.
Note: The following settings must be applied if the KubeVirt storage does not support dynamic provisioning:</description></item></channel></rss>