<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Using Crane on Documentation for Konveyor projects</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/</link><description>Recent content in Using Crane on Documentation for Konveyor projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:36:28 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Step One: Export Resources</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/step1export/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:29:18 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/step1export/</guid><description>The first step of the cluster migration process is exporting resources from a source cluster of any namespace to be input for the subsequent commands.
All of the following export commands will output the contents of the foo namespace into a local export directory with the context demo defined in KUBECONFIG.
crane export -n foo -e export --context demo cat &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF &amp;gt;&amp;gt; conf.yaml namespace: foo export-dir: export context: demo EOF crane export -c conf.</description></item><item><title>Step Two: Transform Exports</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/step2transform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:29:06 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/step2transform/</guid><description>The Transform command facilitates the frequently necessary changes to the exported resources when migrating workloads between one environment to another. For example:
Stripping the resource status information that is no longer relevant after the resource is serialized out of a cluster. Adjusting resource quotas to fit the destination environment. Altering node selectors to match the new environment if the node labels do not match the source environment. Applying custom labels or annotations to resources during the migration.</description></item><item><title>Step Three: Apply Patches</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/step3apply/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 10:28:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/usingcrane/step3apply/</guid><description>The final step of the cluster migration process is to apply all the patches generated by the Transform command to exported resources.
crane apply -e export -t transform -o output Apply the patches in the transform directory to the resources in the export directory and save the modified resource files in the output directory.
After applying the patches, the resources located in output directory can either be deployed to the destination cluster using kubectl apply, or they can be pushed to a repository and then applied with the help of the GitOps pipeline.</description></item></channel></rss>