<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tackle on Konveyor</title><link>http://konveyor.io/tags/tackle/</link><description>Recent content in Tackle on Konveyor</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.io/tags/tackle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Community Update: Konveyor Refocuses Efforts on Replatforming and Refactoring Use Cases</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/community-update-konveyor-refocuses-efforts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/community-update-konveyor-refocuses-efforts/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the latest &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/jyd3mpvVCC4">community update&lt;/a>, we revealed upcoming changes to the Konveyor Project. These adjustments are designed to solve the most important application modernizations problem better and to encourage participation with our community. Here’s what we announced:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We will solely focus on solving for the replatforming and refactoring use cases.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It’s easier to contribute and collaborate with Konveyor thanks to our new special interest group (SIG) model.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can learn the Konveyor project, see upcoming features, and give us feedback at our workshop — part of the OpenShift Commons Gathering at KubeCon NA 2022. &lt;a href="https://hopin.com/events/openshift-commons-gathering-2022-at-kubecon-na-detroit">Register for the Gathering&lt;/a> to secure your spot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tackle 2.1 is available, future Tackle releases will be branded Konveyor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Konveyor roadmap includes migration wave management, multi language support, and integrations with modernization tools.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You can get the details of each announcement below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tackle 2.1 release</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-1-release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-1-release/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the major milestone that &lt;a href="http://konveyor.io/blog/tackle-2-new-capabilities/">Tackle 2.0&lt;/a> represented, the community has continued gathering feedback from the field to further polish the feature set and provide value in the context of modernization, migration and adoption projects. This has led to Tackle 2.1, available now in &lt;a href="https://operatorhub.io/">operatorhub.io&lt;/a>, a minor release that has been focused on stabilizing the project and providing a more streamlined user experience, while still delivering some new tooling. The new features include the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tackle 2: New capabilities for modernizing applications to leverage Kubernetes</title><link>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-new-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.io/blog/2022/tackle-2-new-capabilities/</guid><description>&lt;p>By Ramón Román Nissen&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re thrilled to announce that Tackle 2.0 is now available in &lt;a href="https://operatorhub.io/">operatorhub.io&lt;/a>. This new release marks a major milestone for the Tackle project, with a new architecture focused on enhancing performance, scalability and more importantly, extensibility of the tooling available in the Tackle toolkit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This version includes the seamless integration with the analysis capabilities of the Windup project, enabling Tackle to effectively manage, assess and now also analyze applications to have a holistic view at your portfolio when dealing with large scale modernization and Kubernetes adoption initiatives. This is essential to provide key insights that allow Architects leading these massive projects to make informed decisions, thus reducing risks and making the required effort measurable and predictable.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>