<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tackle 1.0 on Documentation for Konveyor projects</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/</link><description>Recent content in Tackle 1.0 on Documentation for Konveyor projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:17:45 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Upgrading Tackle</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/upgrade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 18:47:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/upgrade/</guid><description>Tackle application instances are upgraded manually.
Upgrading from version 1.1.0 to 1.2.0 Follow the steps below to manually upgrade an instance of the Tackle application from 1.1.0 to 1.2.0.
Prerequisites
Project administrator privileges. Procedure
Important: Specify the namespace and the Tackle instance name for each step.
Update the Keycloak deployment of the Tackle instance: $ kubectl set image -n &amp;lt;namespace&amp;gt; deployment/&amp;lt;tackle_instance&amp;gt;-keycloak keycloak-theme=quay.io/konveyor/tackle-keycloak-init:1.2.0 Update the application-inventory-rest deployment: $ kubectl set image -n &amp;lt;namespace&amp;gt; deployment/&amp;lt;tackle_instance&amp;gt;-application-inventory-rest \ &amp;lt;tackle_instance&amp;gt;-application-inventory-rest=quay.</description></item><item><title>Web Console Services</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/webconsolesvcs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:16:42 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/webconsolesvcs/</guid><description>Tackle web console provides the following services:
Application inventory Assessments Reviews Reports Controls Application inventory The Application inventory page can perform the following tasks:
Manage application portfolios. Define and manage application dependencies. Link applications to the business services that they support. Describe and categorize applications by using tags. Assessments The applications are assessed on the Application inventory page which helps determine the appropriate migration strategy for each application:
Rehosting Replatforming Refactoring Reviews Review a completed assessment on the Application inventory page where the following information is collected from each reviewer:</description></item><item><title>Managing users and credentials</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/manageusers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 16:40:47 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/manageusers/</guid><description>Follow the procedures in this section to manage Tackle users and passwords using the Keycloak admin console.
Accessing the Keycloak admin console A Keycloak admin user is created when Tackle is installed. The admin username and password are needed to log in to the Keycloak admin console. The credentials are stored in the tackle-keycloak secret.
Prerequisites
Cluster-admin privileges. Procedure
Run the following command to obtain the admin credentials: $ kubectl get secret tackle-keycloak -o go-template=&amp;#39;{{range $k,$v := .</description></item><item><title>Managing assessments</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/manageassess/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 15:15:05 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/manageassess/</guid><description>Start, edit, review, and delete application assessments in the Application inventory page of the Tackle web console.
Starting an assessment Follow the steps below to start an application assessment on the Application inventory page of the Tackle web console.
Procedure
Start the Tackle web console Click Application Inventory. Select an application that does not have a Completed assessment status and click the Assess button in the toolbar. Select individual stakeholders or stakeholder groups and then click Next.</description></item><item><title>Managing applications</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/manageapps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 10:51:42 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/manageapps/</guid><description>Managing Applications Follow the procedures in this section to create, import, tag, and modify the applications in the Application inventory page of the Tackle web console.
Creating an application Follow the steps below to create an application on the Application inventory page of the Tackle web console.
Procedure
Open the Tackle web console. Click Application inventory and then Create New. Complete the following fields: Name: Name of the application. Description: Optional.</description></item><item><title>Additional tools</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/additionaltools/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:01:08 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/tackle/tackle1/additionaltools/</guid><description>DIVA Tackle DiVA is a data-centric application analysis tool that imports a set of target application source files and provides database/transaction analysis results.
Test Generator Tackle Test Generator is an automatic test-generation and differential-testing tool that currently supports unit-level test generation for Java applications. (Future project plans include adding capabilities for automated generation of end-to-end UI/UX test cases for web applications and test cases for REST APIs.)
Container Advisor Tackle Container Advisor provides containerization advisory information for a large scale application portfolio.</description></item></channel></rss>