<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorials on Documentation for Konveyor projects</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorials on Documentation for Konveyor projects</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 19:36:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://konveyor.github.io/crane/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stateless application mirror</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/tutorials/statelessappmirror/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 15:18:35 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/tutorials/statelessappmirror/</guid><description>This tutorial is an example of how to mirror a simple, stateless PHP Guestbook application using Crane.
Roadmap
1. Deploy the Guestbook application in the source cluster. 2. Extract resources from the source cluster using Crane Export. 3. Transform resources to prepare manifests for the destination cluster using Crane Transform. 4. Apply the transformations using Crane Apply and apply application manifests to the destination cluster. Prerequisites
Create a source and destination Kubernetes cluster environment in minikube or Kind: minikube wget &amp;#34;https://raw.</description></item><item><title>Migrating a Kubernetes cluster</title><link>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/tutorials/migratek8cluster/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 15:14:19 -0600</pubDate><guid>http://konveyor.github.io/crane/tutorials/migratek8cluster/</guid><description>This tutorial is an example of how to use the Konveyor tool Crane to migrate an application (inventory) from the source Kubernetes cluster (src) to the destination cluster (dest).
Refer to the Crane Documentation for more detailed information.
Note: In addition to migrating with Crane, it is helpful to push the application to Git so it can be automatically deployed to any cluster in the future. This demo includes those steps.</description></item></channel></rss>